[MUSIC]
Stanford University.
>> Network, there's actually a whole
class, I think next quarter,
on just networks for computer vision.
Where they've really
changed the entire field.
In NLP, they've had some impact but
not as much,
which is why we don't have
the entire lecture on just CNNs.
But they are an interesting model family.
They are paralyzable, they're very good
on GPUs, and so we'll sort of look into
them in detail today, understand hopefully
by the end why they're so useful.
And fast to implement on GPUs but really
also give you at least some intuition,
to be honest there's much less intuition
behind some of these very advanced CNN
architectures compared to even some of the
recurrent networks and LSTMs that we had.
So we'll actually start today with
a mini tutorial of Azure and GPUs,
we wanna encourage you all to really get
started on that as soon as possible.
Also, thanks everybody for filling out
the survey I think this one is one
of the important take away messages, which
is overall what do you think of the pace.
We're very happy to see that the majority
are quite happy with the pace.
It's kind of impossible with such
a large class to not be too fast and
not too slow for 100% of everybody, sizznce
people have vastly different backgrounds.
Very sorry for
the little less than a third I think, for
whom it's too fast,
I hope today will be, not quite as fast.
And hopefully, in office hours and so
on we can make up for some of that.
So we'll talk about a couple
of different CNN variants.
We'll have a fun research highlight on
character-aware neural language models.
And then, we'll actually also look
a little bit into tips and tricks that
are slightly more practical, and you'll
observe that these practical details and
tricks actually making this particular CNN
architecture work are super important and
without it you really lose 10% or
so of accuracy.
Look at it a little critically.
At some of the evaluations that
are going on in the field, and
then I will compare a couple of
different models which will lead us to
a very new model called the
quasi-recurrent neural network for treaty,
which just came out
a couple of months ago.
With that, I’ll do one organization
slide before we go onto Azure.
So project advice office hours, I would
really encourage everybody who’s doing
a project to now come to project
advice office hours every week.
I’ve asked groups that I’m
mentoring personally to also
As a server requirement.
Not all the groups were
able to come every week.
I encourage you all to come.
I am keeping track of
whether you're there.
So also for everybody who basically is
still undecided whether they should
move on with their project, you'll
see kind of where PA4 folks should be
at in the next week or so, where you
have to have run some baselines on
your data set by now if you're
doing your final project.
If you don't even have your dataset
ready yet, you can't even run a simple,
let's say, bag of vectors, kinda baseline,
it's starting to be really worrisome,
so definitely make sure you
start running your experiments.
Some simple things, baselines, could be
just any, just could be your regressions.
You download some code somewhere, but
you need to make sure you
have your data set ready.
Otherwise, it'll be too late.
And for
PA4 folks we actually enforce that with
a little additional deadline just
to make sure you're really all.
Going to be able to run it cuz this is
not one of those things that you can
cram really hard and you work 10x and
so you make 10x to progress
because your experiments will take a day
to run and so you run for one day.
Turns out at the end you had a bug and
then the deadline was there and
you have nothing.
So it happens every year.
And we really want to make sure
it doesn't happen this year even
though we're a bigger class.
So we'll talk about that soon.
Also, in terms of positive motivation,
there's actually going to be a really
awesome poster session that
we're putting together,
we have corporate sponsors
that give us some money, and
they will allow us to basically give
out price, have prices for you.
We'll make it public, so
hopefully a lot of folks will show up and
check out your research.
It's a lot of excitement both from various
companies, VCs, if you have a really
awesome poster, who knows, at the end you
may have some funding for your start up.
And we'll have food also, very nice
catering, so should be really fun poster
session, so hopefully you can be very
excited about that and your projects.
Yeah?
Will there be enough food for everybody?
>> [LAUGH]
>> It’s a good question.
We’ll spend thousands and
thousands of dollars on food we hope
there will be enough food for everybody.
Schein is organizing it she's nodding.
Yes.
Any other organizational questions
around the Poster Areas Project.
All right,
then take it away on the GPU side.
>> [INAUDIBLE].
>> Nope, you're good.
>> All right, everyone.
This is just intended to be a short
public service announcement basically
about how to get started with Azure and
why you should get started with Azure.
By now, every team should have received
an email to at least one of your team
members, probably to your Stanford, one of
your Stanford emails, and you'll have this
message which is basically an invitation
to join our CS224N subscription.
And using following the instructions
of this email you should sign up for
basically GPU access.
So far only 161 people have signed up or
teams have signed up out of the 311,
and essentially we want this number
to increase because everyone
should be using GPUs for
reasons that we'll cover very shortly.
And if you have any issues signing up,
then please report the problems
that you have to Piazza post 1830,
which has the form, also screenshotted
there and we'll help you, essentially,
through any of the problems that you
have with their subscriptions, cool.
So then, more important question that
we're gonna go over is why should you
really care about the GPUs.
Well, first, yesterday we actually
announced the milestone for
the final project and the homework.
It's intended to be something
very quick and easy,
just a paragraph of what you've done.
But we expect you to have used I always
experimented with running some code on
a GPU like that and
this will be worth essentially 2% of your
final grade just if you do it or not.
But really down there the better reason
of why you should be using GPU's
is GPU's will train your models much, much
faster over a much, much larger data set.
And specifically,
Microsoft has offered us,
I think 311 MB6 instances
on their 0 cloud.
These use Tesla GPU's, M60,
if you're interested in the model.
The specifications are,
they have a huge number of CUDA cores,
a huge amount of graphics memory, and
they cost a huge amount of money each.
You also get a nice CPU,
as well as a lot of system memory,
to go along with your Instance.
And the key takeaway here
is that these ar not your
average hardware that you
have in your local machine.
There's gonna be way more power, in terms
of the CPU, in terms of the GPU, and
in terms of well, even for the gaming
whatever hardware you have at home.
And the speed-ups will be 10 to 20,
maybe even 100,
depending on the libraries
that you're running.
So in conclusion, please do get started
on Azure as soon as possible, fill out
the form if you run into subscription
issues, come to office hours or
file support tickets if you have technical
problems such as not being able to etc.
And then, also see our step-by-step guide
to just get started with the process.
For Homework 4,
The full assignment handout will go
over essentially all the details.
But decent models will
take a long time to train.
They'll take one hour plus per epoch,
even on a strong GPU,
such as the previously described ones.
If you don't deal with a GPU,
you'll be spending a week, basically,
just to train a baseline model.
And for the final project, if your project
is sufficiently challenging that needs,
well, you have enough data or your problem
is sufficiently challenging, you really do
want to use a GPU if you want to
receive a good score in this class.
And that would be all.
>> Cool.
Thanks, James.
And by decent model he also means
decent implementations, so if your
implementations isn't super well-optimized
it will take you even longer.
So again, not something you can cram on
in the last couple of days of the class.
All right, any questions about Azure or
[INAUDIBLE]?
What if we're not in the same group
between homework three and four?
So recurrent neural networks were
pretty awesome and are pretty awesome
actually and a lot of times the default
model, but they have some issues.
Namely, they can't really
capture phrases in isolation.
They can really only capture a phrase
given it's left side context.
So what do we mean by this?
If I want to have just a representation
of my birth, in this whole sentence,
well recurrent network will
always go from left to right.
And so, that phrase vector up there
isn't going to just capture my birth,
it will also capture the country of.
And so, sometimes when you have
simple classification problems
you might actually just want to
identify that there's a certain word or
phrase in that over all document and
just try to give
the fact that that phrase exist in your
overall document to somewhere higher up in
the final classifier that
actually needs to classify this.
But here,
you will always go from left to right or
even if you have a bidirectional one,
you go from right to left.
But then you have the same problem,
but on the other side.
Namely, the intermediate,
the words in the center of
a longer document might get lost.
You really have to keep track
of them through every iteration.
And, of course, if you're using
LSTMs are better at doing that,
they're better able to say,
don't turn on the forget gate,
keep some things around, keep certain
units on when you see something.
But it requires a lot of the model
to be able to do that perfectly.
And so, in many of the cases you will see
your classifiers only at the very end,
once it has read the whole sentence and
that is not the issue cuz now,
again, the grading has
to flow through this.
And despite all the [INAUDIBLE] and LSTM,
it's even hard for them to keep very
complex kinds of relationships alive
over many, many different time steps.
So that's one issue with RNNs
that CNNs are trying to resolve.
Now, the main idea here is instead of
computing a single representation of
vector at every time step that captures
basically the context on the left so
far what if we could just
compute a phrase vector for
every single phrase that
we have in this sentence.
So if we have here the phrase a country
of my birth, we might compute
in the very first step of this kinds
of convolutional networks if vector for
the country just this
two words in isolation.
Just country of my birth so
basically compute a vector for
all the by grams in the sentence and
then another one maybe for
all the trigrams,
country of my birth, the country.
And then, for all the fourgrams,
the country of my birth.
So hoping that if this was, for instance,
sentiment classification, that one of
these said, not very good, for instance.
And then, if we captured that vector and
we kind of will try to eventually.
Handle and push that vector all
the way to a softmax through some
other forms that I'll describe soon.
But that is basically the idea
of the very first layer
of a convolutional network for NLP.
And this will basically compute
these phrase vectors regardless of
whether that is a grammatical phrase.
So we know from parsing, for instance,
certain phrases like a country
of is not really a proper noun phrase,
it's sort of an odd,
ungrammatical chunk but this motto
really doesn't care linguistic or
cognitive possibility in any
kind of way for language.
And so, people don't read sentences
that way, but you might be
able to eventually compute several of
these representations in parallel.
And that's going to be a big advantage.
So once we compute all these vectors,
we'll group them after, but
we'll get to that in a second.
So you might ask,
what is convolution, anyway?
And so, here is a very simple definition
for any convolutional operator.
So let's look at the simplest
case of a 1d discrete convolution
of a filter over another function,
at a specific point in time.
You'll basically have a filter size,
here M, and
you'll basically multiply just a filter
at different locations of this input.
And so, in computer vision, that will
help us to extract very meaningful
features such as edges from an image and
eventually more complex features.
And for 2d example, which you'll observe
a lot in computer vision, we have this
really great animation here from the
Stanford Unsupervised Feature Learning and
Deep Learning wiki page.
So imagine you had an image
that you see here in green.
And that image, let's say, is only binary.
The first row of this image is 1, 1,
1, 0, 0 and the second row of pixels
of this binary image is 0, 1, 1, 1,
0 and so on, and you have a filter.
And this filter here has number that
you'll see in the small red font here, and
I’ll turn the animation off for a second
so we can look at it without moving.
Now, the filter here is basically 1,
0, 1, 0, 1, 0, 1, 0, 1.
And now every time step
of the convolution,
we’re going to multiply the numbers of
the filter with the numbers off the image.
We multiply, again,
the red numbers from the filter with the,
images, with the image values and
that will result,
basically multiply all of
them then we sum them up.
So very simple in our product if we were
to vectorize these three by three blocks
into, and nine dimensional vector and
we just have a simple inner product
between those two vectors or we just
multiply them here and then sum them up.
So one times one plus one times zero plus
one times one and so on will sum to four.
And we'll basically move
this filter one time step,
one pixel at a time across the image.
So let's look again, this looks like
basically multiply all the numbers and
then sum them up.
And then, we'll move one down, and
again move from left to right.
Any questions, yeah?
That's a great question.
What would be the equivalent
of a pixel in LP and
yes, you're exactly right,
it will be a word vector.
Before I jump there,
are there any more questions about the
general definition of convolution, yeah?
How do we decide on the convolution?
So how do we decide what matrix it is?
The matrix of the convolution
of filter here,
these red numbers are actually
going to be learned.
So you have an input and then you do
back propagation through a network,
we'll get to eventually it'll have
the same kind of cross entropy error,
that we have for all the other ones.
It'll have a softmax and
we're going to basically back propagate
through this entire architecture, and
then we'll actually update the weights
here in this particular example in red.
After they started with
some random initialization.
And then we'll update them and
they'll change.
And what's kind of interesting
in computer vision,
which I won't go into too many details in
this class, but in computer vision they
learn eventually to detect
certain edges in the first layer.
In the second layer they'll learn to
detect certain combinations of edges like
corners, and the third layer they
will learn to basically detect and
have a very high activation,
these guys here.
A very high activation when you see
more complex patterns like stripes and
things like that.
And as you go higher up through
convolution networks and computer vision,
you can actually very nicely
visualize what's going on, and
you identify, like the fifth layer
some neurons actually fire when,
they see a combination of eyes and
a nose and a mouth.
Sadly, for NLP we don't have any of that.
It's one of the reason's they're
not quite as popular in NLP.
Yep.
Sure, so you have here m, you filter.
So in the 1d case, that'll just be, f and
g are just a single number, and
now you're going to move over f.
So imagine this was just one dimension.
And so you move from minus M to M,
as in for the nth time step,
you're going to multiply the filter,
g[m] here,
over this function input, and
basically go one times step, and
you sum up this product between
the two numbers at each time step.
Does that make sense?
So you go from minus m,
which if this is minus and
this is minus, so you start head of n,
n time steps away, and
then you keep multiplying the numbers
until you have the whole sum.
And then you have your convolution
at that discrete time step n.
>> [INAUDIBLE]
>> That's right, m is your window size.
And we'll go over the exact examples for
NLP in much more detail.
Yeah.
How do we figure out the window size?
We'll actually have a bunch of window
sizes, so maybe this is a good side way
to talk about the actual
model that we'll use for NLP.
So this is going to be the first and
most simple variant of
a convolutional network for NLP.
You can [INAUDIBLE] go to town and
towards the end they'll,
show you some examples of how we can
embellish this architecture a lot more.
This one is based on a really seminal
paper by Collobert and Weston from 2011.
And then the very particular model
in its various queuing details,
came from Kim from just three years ago.
Basically the paper title is,
a Convolutional Neural Network for
Sentence Classification.
All right, so as with every model out
there, whenever you wanna write down your
equations, no worries, we're not gonna
go into a lot more derivatives today.
Actually no derivatives,
cuz all the math is really similar
to math we've done before.
But it's really still important to
identify very clearly your notation.
So let's start.
As the question was correctly asked,
we'll actually start with word vectors.
So we'll have at every time step,
I will have a word vector Xi.
And that will be here for
us now a k dimensional vector.
And then we'll represent the entire
sentence through a concatenation.
So we'll use this plus and
circle symbol, for concatenating
the vectors of all the words.
And so we'll describe the entire sentence,
which we'll have for
our definition here,
n-many words to be X from one to n.
And that will be the concatenation
of the first to the nth word vector.
Yeah.
Great question,
are word vectors concatenated length-wise?
Yes.
For now we'll assume they're
all concatenated as a long row.
All right now we'll introduce
this additional notation here, so
we don't just go from one to n, but
we might actually want to extract specific
words in the range,
from time step i to time step i plus j,
or in general some other
number of time steps.
So if I have, for instance x two to four,
then I'll take the second, the third,
and the fourth word vector, and
I just have a long vector with just those
three word vectors concatenated together.
I'll let that sink in,
cuz it's all very simple but
we just need to make sure we
keep track of the notation.
So in general, our convolutional
filter here will be a vector w
of parameters, that we're going
to learn with our standard
stochastic gradient descent-type
optimization methods.
And we'll define this
convolutional filter here,
in terms of its window size and
of course the word vector size.
So h times k, so this is just a vector,
it's not a matrix.
There's no times in between the two.
But let's say we want to have
a convolutional filter that at
each time step, looks at three different
word vectors and tries to combine
them into a single number, or
some kind of feature representation.
What we'll then do is,
basically have a three
times number of dimensions
of each word vector filter.
So I have a very simple example here.
Let's say we have two dimensional
word vectors, of course just for
illustration they'll usually
be 50 dimensional or so.
Let's say we have two
dimensional word vectors, and
we look at three different words in
concatenation at each time step,
we'll basically have
a six dimensional w here.
All right.
So now how do we actually compute
anything and why is it a neural network?
We'll have some non-linearity
here eventually.
Okay but before we get there,
let's look at again,
we have our convolutional filter,
goes looks at h words at each time step.
And again note that w here is
just a single vector; just as
our word vectors are also
concatenated into a single vector.
And now in order to compute
a feature at one time step for this,
what we're going to do is basically just
have an inner product of this w vector of
parameters, times the i-th time
step plus our window size.
So in this case here,
we're going to in the c one for
instance, we'll have W times x one two,
one two three.
So we have here three, so
one plus three minus one goes to three.
So we basically just have
the concatenation of those word
vectors in our product.
Simple sort of multiplication and
sum of all the element wise.
Elements of these vectors.
Then usually,
we'll have our standard bias term and
we'll add a non-linearity at the end.
Any questions about.
That's a great question.
So, as you do this, the question is don't
the words in the middle appear more often.
So here, actually show this example,
and I have actually an animation, so
you are jumping a little bit ahead.
So what happens for instance,
at the very end here, and
the answer will just come
have zeros there for the end.
We'll actually call this
a narrow convolution and
where you can actually have wide
convolutions which we'll get to later,
but yes, you're right the center
words will appear more often,
but really the filters can
adapt to that because you learn
sort of how much you want to care about
any particular input in the filter.
Okay, so
let's define this more carefully so
we can think through the whole process,
yeah?
So the question is,
rephrase it a little bit, what happens
when we have different length sentences?
And there will actually be in two
slides a very clever answer to that.
Which is at some point we'll
add a pooling operator,
which will just look at the maximum
value across everything.
We'll get to that in a second.
And it turns out the length
of the sentence doesn't matter that
much once we do some clever pooling.
How's the size of the filtering
affecting the learning?
Actually quite significantly.
One, the longer your filter is the more
computation you have to do and
the longer context you can capture.
So for instance if you just had a one
d filter it would just multiply and
matrix with every word vector and
it actually would,
you wouldn't gain much, because it would
just transform all the word vectors, and
you may as well store
transformed word vectors.
As you go to longer filters, you'll
actually be able to capture more phrases,
but now you'll also more
likely to over-fit your model.
So that will actually be, the size of
your filter will be hyperparameter, and
there are some tricks.
Namely, you have multiple filters for
multiple lengths,
which we'll get to in a second, too,
that will allow you to get rid of that.
Alright, so, let's say again here,
we have our sentence,
now we have all these possible windows or
length h,
starting at the first word vector,
going to this, and so on.
And now what the means is, since we do
this computation here at every time step,
we'll have basically what
we call a feature map.
And we will capitalize this
here as having a vector
of lots of these different c values.
And again, each c value was
just taking that same w and
having inter-products with a bunch of
the different windows at each time stamp.
Now, this c vector is going to be
a pretty long, n-h+1 dimensional vector.
And it's actually going to
be of different length,
depending on how many words we have.
Which is a little odd, right?
Because in the end, if we want to
plug it into a softmise classifier,
we would want to have
a fixed dimensional vector.
But, intuitively here, we'll just, again,
multiply each of these numbers and
our w here with the concatenation,
and remove along.
Turns out we'll zero pad.
And if you now think carefully, you'll
actually realize, well, I kind of cheated
because really that's what we really
should've done also on the left side.
So on the left side we will actually
also zero pad the sentence.
So we do exactly the same in
the beginning at the end of the sentence.
All right, now, because we have a variable
length vector at this point, and we want
to have eventually a fixed dimensional
feature vector that represents that whole
sentence, what we'll now do is introduce a
new type of building block that we haven't
really looked at that much before, namely,
a pooling operator or pooling layer.
And in particular, what we'll use
here is a so-called max-over-time or
max pooling layer.
And it's a very simple idea,
namely that we're going to capture
the most important activation.
So as you have different elements
figured computed for every window,
you have the hope that the inner
product would be particularly large for
that filter, if it sees a certain
kind of phrase, all right?
So, namely, if you have, let's say your
word vectors are relatively normalized,
if you do an inner product,
you would want to have a very large cosine
similarity between the filter and the
certain pattern that you're looking for.
And that one filter would only be
good at picking up that pattern.
So for instance,
you might hope all your positive words
are in one part of the vector space and
now you have a two dimensional,
sorry a two word vector, sorry.
A filter size of length two
that looks at bigrams, and
you want to ideally have
that filter be very good and
have a very large inner product with
all the words that are positive.
And that would then be captured by having
one of these numbers be very large.
And so what this intuitively allows
you to do is, as you move over it and
you then in the end max pool,
if you just have one word pair,
one biagram that it has a very large
activation for that particular filter w,
you will basically get
that to your c hat here.
And it can ignore all
the rest of the sentence.
It's just going to be able to pick
out one particular bigram very,
very accurately, or a type of bigram.
And because word vectors cluster and
where similar kinds of words
have similar kinds of meaning,
you might hope that all the positive words
will activate a similar kind of filter.
Now the problem with this is, of course,
that that is just a single number, right?
C hat is just a maximum number here
of all the elements in this vector.
So I would just be five.
So that could be one activation.
If we use a relu nonlinearity here,
this will just be a single number.
So c hat is just that.
Now of course, we want to be able to do
more than just find one particular type of
bigram or trigram, we want to have many
more features that we can extract.
And that's why we're going
to have multiple filters w.
So instead of just convolving
a single feature w,
we'll convolve multiple of them.
And as we train this model,
eventually we hope that some of the w
filters will fire and be very active and
have very large inter-products with
particular types of bigrams or
trigrams, or even four grams.
So it's also very useful to have some
filters that only pick out bigrams and
you can actually get quite far with that.
But then maybe you have someone,
some examples where you say for
sentiment again very simply example
it's not very good or risk missing
a much originality and
now you want to have diagrams in filters
of length K times 3.
And so, we can have multiple different
window sizes and at the end, each time we
convolve that filter and we do all
these inner products at each time step.
We'll basically max pool to get a single
number for that filter for that sentence.
If we have different filters
of different lengths,
how do we make sure they
learn different feature?
Of same length or different lengths, yeah.
Of same length, how do we make sure
they learn different features?
Well, they all start at different
random initializations, so
that helps to break up some symmetry.
And then actually we don't have
to do anything in particular
to make sure that happens,
it actually just happens.
So as we do SGD,
from the random initializations,
different filters will move and start
to pick up different patterns in order
to maximize our overall
objective function.
Which we'll get to,
it'll just be logistic regression.
They would probably still
learn different values, yeah.
You update so in the beginning,
well, if they're exactly the same,
basically, as you pool, right,
you will eventually pick,
during backpropagation,
the max value here.
The max value will come,
eventually, from a specific filter.
And if they have the exact same,
one, you would never do it.
But two, if you did,
they would have the exact same value.
And then your computer will have to
choose, randomly, one to be the max.
And if they're just the same,
whatever, it'll pick one and
then it'll backpropagate
through that particular filter.
And then,
they're also going to be different in the
iteration of your optimization algorithm.
Yeah?
>> Is there a reason why
we do the max [INAUDIBLE]?
>> Is there a reason why we do the max?
So in theory nothing would
prevent us from using min too.
Though we in many cases use rectified
linear units which will be max 0x.
And so max pooling makes a lot more
sense cuz min will often just be 0.
And so, we've rallies together,
it makes the most sense to use
the max pooling layer also.
Could we use average pooling?
It's actually not totally crazy,
there are different papers that explore
different pooling schemes and there's no
sort of beautiful mathematical reason
of why one should work better but
intuitively what you're trying to do here
is you try to really just fire when
you see a specific type of engram.
And when you see that
particular type of engram,
cuz that filter fired very strongly for
it, then you wanna say this happened.
And you want to give that signal
to the next higher layer.
And so that is particularly easy if you
choose a specific single value versus
averaging, where you kind of
conglomerate everything again.
And the strong signal that you may get
from one particular unigram, or bigram, or
trigram, might get washed
out in the average.
Great question, so once we have a bunch of
different c hats from each of the filters,
how do we combine them?
And the answer will be,
we'll just concatenate all them.
We'll get to that in a second.
Yeah, so the main idea is once you do
max pooling one of the values will
be the maximum and then all of the other
ones will basically have 0 gradients cuz
they don't change the layer above,
and then you just flow your gradients
through the maximum value
that triggered that filter.
So the question is, doesn't that make
our initialization very important, and
lead to lots of downstream problems?
And the answer is yes,
so likewise if you, for
instance, initialize all your filter
weights such as your rectified
linear units all return zero then,
you're not gonna learn anything.
So you have to initialize your
weights such that in the beginning,
most of your units are active and
something will actually happen.
And then the main trick to, or the way,
the reason why it doesn’t hurt
a ton to have these different
randomizations, you have lots filters.
And each filter can start to pick up
different kinds of signals during
the optimization.
But, in general, yes,
these models are highly non-convex and
if you initialize them incorrectly,
they won’t learn anything.
But we have relatively
stable initialization
schemes at this point that
just work in most cases.
Great questions, all right I like it.
All right, so we basically now have,
we're almost at the final model.
But there's another idea here And
that combines what we've learned about
word vectors, but extends it a little bit.
And namely, instead of representing the
sentence only as a single concatenation
of all the word vectors, we'll actually
start with two copies of that.
And then we're going to backpropagate into
one of these two channels and
not into the other.
So why do we do this?
Remember we had this lecture where
I talked about the television and
the telly, and
as you back-propagate into word vectors,
they start to move away from their
Glove or word2vec initialization.
So again, just quick recap,
word vectors are really great.
We can train them on a very
large unsupervised scope so
they capture semantic similarities.
Now if you start backpropagating your
specific task into the word vectors,
they will start to move around.
When you see that word vector in your
supervised classification problem in that
dataset.
Now what that means is as you
push certain vectors that you see
in your training data sets somewhere else,
the vectors that you don't see in your
training data set stay where they are and
now might get misclassified if
they only appear in the test set.
So by having these two channels We'll
basically try to have some of the goodness
of really trainings,
the first copy of the word vectors
to be really good on that task.
But the second set of word vectors to
stay where they are, have the good, nice,
general semantic similarities in vector
space goodness that we have from unlarge
and supervised word vectors.
And in this case here, both of these
channels are actually going to be added to
each of the CIs before we max-pool, so
we will pool over both of those channels.
Now, the final model, and this is the
simplest, one I'll get to you in a second.
Is basic just concatenating
all this c hats,
so remember each c hats
was one max pool filter.
And we have this case here
that say m many filters.
And so our final feature vector for
that sentence,
has just an r n-dimensional vector,
where we have m many different fil